

GIRISH GOPAUL

• DETAILS •

Mahébourg Mauritius +230 59010577 girish@gopaul.me

SKILLS

React & Redux

Ruby on Rails

JavaScript & TypeScript

Nodejs & Expressis

Git

Elixir's Phoenix

Angular

Python & Django

Java

Flutter

PHP

C++

Linux

Redis

Vue.js & Svelte

NGINX Server

LINKS

LinkedIn

girish.gopaul.me

Personal blog

LANGUAGES

English

French

PROFILE

Introduced to computer programming at the age of 14 by my father, I instantly fell in love with software development. I grew into becoming an extremely passionate and versatile developer with code quality as a core value. I am always excited to learn new frameworks and programming languages. Challenging tasks gets me pumped all the time. I have now been working professionally for 6+ years and my two favorite go-to framework are **Ruby on Rails** and **React**.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Frontend Developer at inspexion.com

February 2023 — Present

Created v2 of inspexion.com with React (and typescript) **from scratch**. Implemented jest, react-testing-library, storybook, eslint & prettier, i18n and jotai as state management solution.

Senior Fullstack Dev at Contractbook, Copenhagen - Remote

October 2021 — January 2023

At Contractbook and I worked with **React** and **Elixir's Phoenix** (similar to **Rails**). Apart from feature development, I enjoyed doing a lot of refactor of old React class components to newer **functional components** in **typescript**. I also love doing SQL queries neatly using Phoenix's **Ecto**.

Software Developer at Elca, Ebene, Mauritius

September 2020 — October 2021

At Elca, I was given the role of Front-End developer, I worked mostly with **Angular** and **React**

Consultant at Spoon Consulting, Mauritius

July 2017 — September 2020

At Spoon Consulting I was immediately assigned to work with **Ruby on Rails** and **Angularjs** as **full-stack** developer. I have also worked with other various technologies such as developing **NPM** modules for **Nodejs** and **AWS Serverless**.

EDUCATION

BSc (Hons) Computer Science, University of Mauritius

August 2014 — July 2017

CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Network Associate

Oracle Certified Java Associate

Zend Certified Engineer 2017-PHP